export const GEOGRAPHYA2016 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The scale of the map in statement form is",
A: "1 centimetre on the map represents 1 kilometre on the ground.",
B: "2 centimetres on the map represent 1 kilometre on the ground.",
C: "3 centimetres on the map represent 1 kilometre on the ground.",
D: "4 centimetres on the map represent 1 kilometre on the ground.",
answer: "A. 1 centimetre on the map represents 1 kilometre on the ground.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Farming is common in the",
A: "North western part of the map.",
B: "North eastern part of the map.",
C: "South western part of the map.",
D: "South eastern part of the map.",
answer: "D. South eastern part of the map.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The western part of R. Gembeh flows through",
A: "A delta.",
B: "A gorge.",
C: "A levee.",
D: "An undulating plain.",
answer: "B. A gorge.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The point where R. Isbo meets R. Gembeh is called",
A: "An entreport.",
B: "A watershed.",
C: "A lagoon.",
D: "A confluence.",
answer: "D. A confluence.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The contour interval on the map is",
A: "50 metres.",
B: "100 metres.",
C: "150 metres.",
D: "200 metres.",
answer: "A. 50 metres.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The lowest point in the mapped area is in the",
A: "South east.",
B: "North east.",
C: "South west.",
D: "North west.",
answer: "B. North east.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The distance as a crow flies from Bebe to Bodel is",
A: "12.75 km.",
B: "10.00 km",
C: "7.25 km.",
D: "5.25 km.",
answer: "B. 10.00 km",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The bearing of Bodel from Bebe is",
A: "25.0°",
B: "255.0°",
C: "115.0°",
D: "150.0°",
answer: "B. 255.0°",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following statement is true about the drainage of the mapped area?",
A: "The watershed from which the rivers take their sources is in the North West.",
B: "R. Isbo and R. Gembeh are the two rivers that drain the district.",
C: "R. Gembeh has many tributaries.",
D: "An ox-bow lake has been formed at the point of intersection of R. Isbo and R. Gembeh.",
answer: "B. R. Isbo and R. Gembeh are the two rivers that drain the district.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. The common modes of transportation in the mapped area are",
A: "Railway and water.",
B: "Pipeline and railway.",
C: "Road and water.",
D: "Air and water.",
answer: "C. Road and water.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. What is the name of the diagram above?",
A: "Line graph",
B: "Bar graph",
C: "Pie chart",
D: "Star graph",
answer: "B. Bar graph",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. How much rice was produced in 2010 by Country X?",
A: "10,000 kilogrammes",
B: "20,000 kilogrammes",
C: "50,000 kilogrammes",
D: "60,000 kilogrammes",
answer: "C. 50,000 kilogrammes",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The total production of rice in kilogrammes by Country X from 2007 to 1010 was",
A: "60,000.",
B: "105,000.",
C: "200,000",
D: "260,000.",
answer: "B. 105,000.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. In which year did Country X have the highest production of rice?",
A: "2007",
B: "2008",
C: "2009",
D: "2010",
answer: "D. 2010",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The planet which revolves around the sun in a clockwise direction is",
A: "Jupiter.",
B: "Mars.",
C: "Saturn.",
D: "Uranus.",
answer: "D. Uranus.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. In the southern hemisphere, the Summer Solstice falls on",
A: "21st March.",
B: "22st December.",
C: "23rd September.",
D: "23rd June.",
answer: "B. 22nd December.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The planet with the shortest orbit around the sun is",
A: "Jupiter.",
B: "Mars.",
C: "Mercury.",
D: "Pluto.",
answer: "C. Mercury.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. What will be the time in Sao Luis Brazil (Longitude 45° W) when it is noon in London (Longitude 0°)?",
A: "10.00 pm",
B: "10.00 am",
C: "9.00 am",
D: "7.20 am",
answer: "C. 9.00 am",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Isotherm is a line joining places of equal",
A: "Cloud cover.",
B: "Pressure.",
C: "Rainfall.",
D: "Temperature.",
answer: "D. Temperature.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. The ozone layer is found in the",
A: "Exosphere.",
B: "Ionosphere.",
C: "Stratosphere.",
D: "Troposphere.",
answer: "C. Stratosphere.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Calculate the distance between the Equator (Latitude 0°) and a city Z in Egypt (Latitude 30° N).",
A: "3,300 km.",
B: "3,000 km.",
C: "3,330 km.",
D: "4,430 km.",
answer: "C. 3,330 km.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following climatic belts has the highest diurnal temperature range?",
A: "Desert",
B: "Mediterranean",
C: "Tropical Continental",
D: "Tropical Hinterland",
answer: "A. Desert",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following gases is found in very little quantity in the atmosphere?",
A: "Argon",
B: "Carbon dioxide",
C: "Nitrogen",
D: "Oxygen",
answer: "B. Carbon dioxide",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Circular depressions formed in the bed of an upper course riser is known as",
A: "Interlocking spurs.",
B: "Plunge pools.",
C: "rapids",
D: "potholes.",
answer: "D. potholes.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Temperature inversion occurs",
A: "Warm air rises over cold air in the tropics.",
B: "Temperature remains the same with height.",
C: "Temperature increases with horizontal distance.",
D: "Temperature increases with height.",
answer: "D. Temperature increases with height.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The most satisfactory explanation for the formation of fold mountain is",
A: "Faulting.",
B: "Vulcanicity",
C: "Compressional forces.",
D: "Tensional forces.",
answer: "C. Compressional forces.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The cooling and solidification of magma within the earth’s crust results in the formation of a",
A: "Cinder cone.",
B: "Composite cone.",
C: "Laccolith.",
D: "Lava plateau.",
answer: "C. Laccolith.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. In an oasis, water is derived from",
A: "Bajada.",
B: "Underground.",
C: "Rainfall.",
D: "Playa.",
answer: "B. Underground.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The unfolded portion of a fold mountain is called",
A: "Sial.",
B: "Anticline.",
C: "Syncline.",
D: "Sill.",
answer: "B. Anticline.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following features is produced as a result of river capture?",
A: "Wind gap",
B: "River terrace",
C: "Gorge",
D: "Incised mender",
answer: "A. Wind gap",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Tilting of tree trunks, poles and piling of soil behind a wall are all effects of",
A: "Mud flow.",
B: "Soil creep.",
C: "Rock slide.",
D: "zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
answer: "B. Soil creep.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Exfoliation of rock is as a result of",
A: "Weathering by oxidation.",
B: "Weathering by means of solution.",
C: "Mechanical weathering.",
D: "Biological weathering.",
answer: "C. Mechanical weathering.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Spits are formed by",
A: "Ocean currents and trade winds.",
B: "Wave erosion.",
C: "Longshore drift and wave deposition.",
D: "Westerly winds.",
answer: "C. Longshore drift and wave deposition.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. A water table can be described as",
A: "A pool of underground water.",
B: "A line connecting underground springs of equal height.",
C: "A line indicating the depth of all artesian wells in an area",
D: "The general level of underground water in an area.",
answer: "D. The general level of underground water in an area.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Leaching is the",
A: "Accumulation of soil minerals in one layer of soil.",
B: "Washing down of soil nutrients.",
C: "Erosion of soil from steep slopes.",
D: "Loss of soil moisture.",
answer: "B. Washing down of soil nutrients.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Which of the following features are found in limestone regions?",
A: "Swallowholes",
B: "Barchans",
C: "Buttes",
D: "Inselbergs",
answer: "A. Swallowholes",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. When the roof of a natural arch collapses, the resulting rock pillar left standing in the sea is called.",
A: "Headland.",
B: "Stack.",
C: "Tombolo.",
D: "Wave-cut platform.",
answer: "B. Stack.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The high temperature in the interior of the earth may result in the formation of",
A: "Fold mountains.",
B: "Horst.",
C: "Geyser.",
D: "Rift valley.",
answer: "C. Geyser.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Africa is described as the most tropical of all continents because",
A: "Most part of Africa lies within the tropics.",
B: "It lies astride the Greenwich Meridian.",
C: "It is far from the Equator.",
D: "It is near the poles.",
answer: "A. Most part of Africa lies within the tropics.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The introduction of ECOWAS passport among member countries is to promote",
A: "Economic co-operation.",
B: "Trade amongst member states.",
C: "Free movement of people in the sub-region.",
D: "Cultural co-operation.",
answer: "C. Free movement of people in the sub region.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Elements such as wind, water vapour, sunlight, and gases which are of benefit to man animals and plants are called",
A: "Human resource.",
B: "Atmospheric resources.",
C: "Vegetation resources.",
D: "Water resources.",
answer: "B. Atmospheric resources.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following is not a timber producing country?",
A: "Gabon",
B: "Nigeria",
C: "Cote d’Ivoire",
D: "Senegal",
answer: "D. Senegal",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. What is the name of trade between one country and another?",
A: "Domestic trade",
B: "Internal trade",
C: "International trade",
D: "Inter-state trade",
answer: "C. International trade",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Which of the following settlements is famous for its ecclesiastical function?",
A: "Freetown",
B: "London",
C: "Lagos",
D: "Rome",
answer: "D. Rome",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Which of the following cities is both a harbour and a capital?",
A: "Accra",
B: "Abidjan",
C: "Banjul",
D: "Abuja",
answer: "B. Abidjan",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Irrigation projects are commonly found in areas of",
A: "Low and unreliable rainfall.",
B: "High surface fluctuations.",
C: "Low rate of evaporation.",
D: "High volume of rainfall.",
answer: "A. Low and unreliable rainfall.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. All the following lead to the depletion of the ozone layer except",
A: "Volcanic eruptions.",
B: "Bush burning.",
C: "Combustion of coal and oil.",
D: "Evapotranspiration",
answer: "D. Evapotranspiration",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. More Hydro-Electric Power (H.E.P) projects should be constructed in developing countries because",
A: "There is abundant rainfall.",
B: "There is ever increasing demand for power.",
C: "Skilled labour is abundant.",
D: "There are many waterfalls on their rivers.",
answer: "B. There is ever increasing demand for power.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. It is light in weight, a good conductor of electricity and used extensively in the manufacture of aircraft. This is a vivid description of",
A: "Aluminium.",
B: "Iron.",
C: "Uranium.",
D: "Silver.",
answer: "A. Aluminium.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. A village is characterized by",
A: "The presence of several refineries.",
B: "Availability of tertiary health care facilities.",
C: "Developed infrastructural facilities.",
D: "Agriculture and other primary economic activities.",
answer: "D. Agriculture and other primary economic activities.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]